MARÍA DE LOS ÁNGELES LASA

Political Data Scientist

@ ma.angeleslasa@gmail.com **❤** @Condolasa

in marialasa

marialasa.ar marialasa



ABOUT ME

Political Data Scientist with 10+ years of experience in mixed methods research. Currently helping governments, CSOs, and NGOs to conduct research, measure, evaluate, and report the impact of their initiatives.

I have led technical projects related to media literacy, mis- and disinformation, judicial protection of Venezuelan migrants, migrant integration, affective polarization, participation of women in politics, "anti-vax" movements, COVID-19, and sports for development (S4D).

Excellent communication skills to present technical analysis to nontechnical audiences.

EXPERIENCE

Data Analytics Lead

Gender Justice Data Hub, Global Fund for Women

Dec 2022 - Ongoing

San Francisco, US (Remote)

Director of Legacy and Sustainability

XIX Pan American and Parapan American Games Santiago 2023

May 2022 - Dec 2022

Santiago, CL

Research and Data Analytics Manager

Movilizatorio

Apr 2020 - Apr 2022

Bogotá, CO (Remote)

Open Data Policy Advisor

Unit of Open Government, OECD **i** Jul 2019 - Sep 2019

Paris, FR

Project Consultant

Oxford Development Consultancy

Ct 2018 - Mar 2019

Oxford, UK

Head of Legacy and Sustainability

Buenos Aires 2018 Youth Olympic Games

Apr 2017 - Sep 2018

Buenos Aires, AR

AML/CFT Compliance Officer

Financial Intelligence Unit of Argentina

Ct 2016 - Mar 2017

Buenos Aires, AR

EDUCATION

Master of Public Policy **University of Oxford (GB)**

Sep 2018 - Nov 2019

Ph.D. in Political Science Università degli Studi di Camerino (IT)

i Jun 2011 - Dec 2014

B.A. in International Relations Universidad Católica de Córdoba (AR)

Feb 2004 - Feb 2009

STRENGTHS

Writing Skills Storytelling Creativity **Public Speaking Analytical Skills**

TECHNICAL SKILLS

SPSS R Python HTML MT_FX MS Excel Tableau Gephi Flourish

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native **English: Fluent** Italian: Intermediate



HONORS & AWARDS



TEDxSpeaker

TEDxUCC & TEDxRecoleta, 2016







RESEARCH & TEACHING

Associate Professor of Politics of Policymaking Universidad Comunera

Aug 2020 - Ongoing

Asunción, PY (Remote)

Guest Lecturer of State Theory and Public Policy Universidad Torcuato Di Tella

a Aug 2021 – Jan 2022

Buenos Aires, AR

Visiting Researcher @ Department of Pol.Sci. Universidad de Los Andes

Sep 2013 - Nov 2013

Bogotá, CO

Visiting Researcher @ LLILAS

University of Texas at Austin

Feb 2013 - Aug 2013

Austin, US

Graduate Teaching Assistant in Introduction to IR Universidad Nacional de Villa María

Feb 2009 - Dec 2009

Villa María, AR

GRANTS & SCHOLARSHIPS

Erasmus+ Grant

UOxford-OECD Summer Placement (FR), 2019. €800.

iTrek Scholarship

Oxford-Blavatnik Policy Programme (IL), 2019.

Blavatnik Scholarship

University of Oxford (GB), 2018 - 2019. £7,376.

Chevening Award

British Government (GB), 2018 - 2019. £47,569.

Fulbright Scholarship

UMass Young Leaders Program (US), 2014. U\$8,000.

CUIA Scholarship

Italian Government (IT), 2011 - 2014. €72,200.

Fundación Carolina Scholarship

Complutense Summer School (ES), 2011. €4,000.

PUBLICATIONS

 LASA, M. (2024). País de vinalón: mi viaje a Corea del Norte. Buenos Aires: CADAL. ISBN: 978-987-4492-15-9.

 ARGARAÑÁZ, M.; LASA, M. et al. (2018). Protocolo para la gestión de eventos sostenibles. United Nations Argentina & UNDP.

OTHER STUDIES

PgDipl. in Territorial Big Data FLACSO (AR)

Apr 2023 - Mar 2024

Data Science Summer School Hertie School Data Science Lab (DE)

Jul 2022 - Aug 2022

PgCert. in Data Science Universidad Torcuato Di Tella (AR)

Apr 2020 - Oct 2020

PgDipl. in Policy Evaluation Universitat Pompeu Fabra (ES)

Mar 2017 - Dec 2017

AFFILIATIONS

National

Chevening Alumni¹, CARI², CADAL³

- ¹ Board of Directors, 2020 2024
- ² Executive Board YG, 2018 & 2021
- ³ Academic Council, 2022-2024

International

Oxford Union, R-Ladies Global, Red de Politólogas & YLAI

VOLUNTEER WORK

OxCGRT, University of Oxford Data Analyst, 2020 – 2021

South American Business Forum Contest Jury, 2012 - Ongoing

Model United Nations (MUN)
Academic Advisor, 2005 - Ongoing

CAUSES

Gender Equality Civic Tech

Democracy and participation Education

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Cold War DPRK Bass Violin
Podcasts Blogs Photography Tetris
Lego Travels Space Exploration